WILLIAM WARNER

2023 Higbee Avenue, Memphis, TN 38104 | 901-292-6465 | will.r.warner@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Mechanical Engineer with 8 years of professional experience in design, project management, and field support across multiple industries. Skilled at working in teams and utilizing problem-solving and time-management abilities to deliver results in a safe, timely, and effective manner.

Education

Mississippi State University – Bachelor of Science – Mechanical Engineering Overall GPA: 4.0

December 2012

Experience

Project Engineer – Diversified Conveyors, Intl. – Memphis, TN

2016 - Present

- Performed as Lead Engineer and oversaw 9 junior engineers on a ~\$400 million project
- Developed installation drawing packages for conveyor equipment and related structures
- Worked with structural engineering firms to design and fabricate platforms and support structures
- Designed conveyor and structural models using AutoCAD 2D and 3D and Autodesk Inventor
- Created conveyor and component drawings
- Coordinated with Project Managers to ensure deliverables were completed on time and in accordance with the contract specifications
- Developed new drafting techniques to increase productivity

Design Engineer – Chevron Corporation – Richmond, CA

2013 - 2016

- Generated engineering work packages and drawings for complex repairs to refinery equipment
- Performed as Lead Engineer for 2 plant outages with a total expenditure of \$23 million
- Developed purchased specifications for heat exchangers and other equipment totaling ~\$250,000
- Reviewed and approved fabrication drawings for purchased equipment
- Worked with Materials Engineers to specify material requirements for equipment
- Analyzed inspections and test data with Inspectors and Technicians to develop repair plans
- Optimized work scope on a project to reduce installation costs by \$20,000
- Supervised engineers during plant outages and mentored interns

Reliability Intern - Valero Energy Corporation - Memphis, TN

Summer 2012

- Worked with senior engineers to develop plans for refinery equipment upgrades
- Developed a database for tracking refinery equipment

Engineering Co-op – Hunter Engineering Co. – Durant, MS

2010 - 2011

- Worked with senior engineers on quality control issues and factory upgrades
- Created a database for quality control inspection equipment
- Determined root causes of manufacturing issues and developed solutions to these issues

Related Skills

- Highly proficient in AutoCAD and AutoCAD Architecture (2D and 3D)
- Proficient in Autodesk Inventor, Solidworks, and Mathcad
- Competent in IBC, OSHA, ASME B31.3, ASME Section VIII-Div. 1, and ASTM codes
- Knowledgeable in Visual Basic for Applications, Vizio, Powerpoint, Excel, Word, Access, and Project